Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother James.
>> Yes, sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain, for the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou
labor, and do all thy work. But the
seventh day is the Sabbath of the Lord
thy God. In it thou shalt not do any
work, thou nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hollowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill, thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor as
man's servant, nor as maid's servant,
nor as ox, nor asked, nor anything that
is thy neighbors. I read Exodus 20:es
1-1 17. May the Lord add a blessing to
the reading of this word. In Jesus name
we pray. Amen.
Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and the
long scripture questions as well as
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just ask
that you please keep them to a two
scripture maximum per question. But let
me introduce to you the family that's on
the panel this evening. We got brother
Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> We got brother Jerome.
>> Grace in peace.
>> We got brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> We got brother James.
>> Good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Sean.
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
and I'm brother Cornell. What is our
first question of the program?
>> Uh yes, there are tonight's questions
from November the 19, 2025. We will
answer first before getting into
tonight's Q&A. So Zion asked in Matthew
4:es 5 and 8, "Was Satan physically
there with Jesus or was Jesus being led
by Satan in his mind?" I say he was
physically there because it said he
taketh but a friend say no.
>> All right. So Matthews 4:5
Uh
>> and verse eight. Was uh Satan literally
there or was it just a mind thing?
>> He was literally and physically there
and you are right. Don't matter what
people say. What do the book say? Let's
go to Matthew 4 James in at verse one.
>> Okay. Matthew 4:1 says, "Then was Jesus
led up of the spirit into the wilderness
to be tempted of the devil." Give me
verse three.
>> And when the tempter came to him,
>> And when the tempter And when the
tempter came to him,
>> go ahead.
>> He said, "If thou be the son of God,
command that these stones be made
bread."
>> Skip down to verse 5.
Then the devil taketh him up into the
holy city and setth him on a pinnacle of
the temple.
Jesus overcame that. Give me verse eight
>> again. The devil taken him up into an
exceeding high mountain and showeth him
all the kingdoms of the world and the
glory of them.
>> Skip down to verse 11.
Then the devil leaveth him, and behold,
angels came and ministered unto him.
>> James uh Job 1 quickly.
Job 1 verse 6.
Job 1 verse 6 says, "Now there was a day
when the sons of God came to present
themselves before the Lord and Satan
came also among them."
>> He came with them. He just didn't come
up under the title sons of God cuz he
was disinherited.
>> He came with him just like he came to
Jesus. Just like when Jesus said, "Let
gu get thee behind me." He he left him
tempting him. My last place, Luke 10.
Luke 10, one verse. Luke 10
and one verse. Look what Jesus said.
Luke 10 and verse 18.
Luke 10 and verse 18 says, "And he said
unto them, I beheld Satan as lightning
fall from heaven."
>> Of course, he kicked him out. In
Revelation the 12th chapter, he kicked
him out. him and his angels. And
he said right here, I saw him when he
got kicked out, when he fell from from
the third heaven to earth. So sisters
and brothers, the book says this was a
physical event. And I forgot to tell
you, spirit beings can see other spirit
beings.
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered that question. As we move on to
our next
>> next one, Malikica Banks asks, "How do
you know when to stop trying to share
truth with family members who refuse to
receive it even when you show them
scripture?"
>> All right. So, how do you know when to
stop when you showing all these
scriptures? Brother Dre,
>> let's go over to u Matthew the 10th
chapter and we going to look at a verse
there. You know, you want to share with
your family. I get it. You want them to
get it. But you got to know, we going to
read a couple of things and it's going
to tell you. Matthew 10 and 14. Go
ahead, brother. Then you get it.
>> Okay. Matthew 10:14 says, "And whosoever
shall not receive you, nor hear your
words when ye depart out of that house
or city, shake off the dust of your
feet."
So, if they don't want to hear it, then
you don't want to keep telling them
because they telling you they don't want
to hear it and you reading scripture to
them. But, you know, you love your
family and you want them to hear it.
Now, let's go over to uh 1 Corinthians
3. 1 Corinthians 3. And we going to read
one verse there. 1 Corinthians 3 and
read verse six.
1 Corinthians 3:6 says, "I have planted
Apollo or I have planted Apollos
watered, but God gave the increase."
>> And that's how you got to look at it.
You plant the seed, another one water,
and God gave the increase. Make sure
that you set the example of being what
God chose you to be. Be be the example
because they looking at you all the
time. Let's go over to Isaiah 55 now.
This the last place. Isaiah 55 and we
going to look at verse 11 there. And
keep this in mind. Isaiah 55 and 11.
Read it when you get it, brother.
So shall my word be that goeth forth out
of my mouth. It shall not return unto me
void, but it shall accomplish that which
I please, and it shall prosper in the
thing whereto I sent it. So if God gave
you a word to give, it ain't going to
return back to him void. It's going to
accomplish what it set out to do. And
whether they hear or whether therefore
bear, they going to hear it. It is their
choice whether they will adhere to it.
That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question. As we
move on to our next
one, Tanya Lian says, "Someone told me
that Sunday worship is not forbidden and
you can worship God any day of the week.
Please help me explain why Saturday and
Sunday worships are not the same."
All right, brother Jerome. Sounds like
it's the Saturday versus Sunday
showdown. What you got? [clears throat]
>> Yeah, I've been in hearing that for a
long time that you can worship God any
day. And that's true. You can He require
us to worship him every day, but every
day is not the Sabbath. Okay? And the
Sabbath according to the Bible and
according the God of this Bible is the
seventh day which they call Saturday.
Okay? That specific day the Lord
sanctified and he hollowed it and he
told us to not do any work. And so if
that was to apply that every day, we
will starve to death. That's why every
day ain't the Sabbath. Okay? But you can
worship God every day. But the Sabbath
day, he sanctified it and set it apart
from the other days. And he told us not
to do any work on the Sabbath day. And
he said, "Don't do your own pleasure on
his holy day." Okay? And he don't want
us to kill no fire on that on his holy
Sabbath day. Okay? So let's go to Exodus
20. We going to read verse 8 through 11
and then we going to go to Isaiah 56
after that.
Exodus 20:8-11.
Okay, it says, "Remember the Sabbath day
to keep it holy. Six days shalt thou
labor and do all thy work, but the
seventh day is the Sabbath of the Lord
thy God. In it thou shalt not do any
work. thou, nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hollowed it. Mhm. And let's go to Isaiah
56 and read verse 1-7. And that'll be
it.
>> Okay. Isaiah 56:es 1-7 says, "Thus
sayeth the Lord, keep ye judgment and do
justice, for my salvation is near to
come, and my righteousness to be
revealed. Blessed is the man that doeth
this, and the son of man that layeth
hold on it, that keepeth the Sabbath
from polluting it, and keepeth his hand
from doing any evil. Neither let the son
of the stranger that has joined himself
to the Lord speak, saying, The Lord hath
utterly separated me from his people.
Neither let the unic say, Behold, I am a
dry tree. For thus sayeth the Lord unto
the Unix that keep my Sabbaths and
choose the things which please me and
take hold of my covenant. Even unto them
will I give in mine house and within my
walls a place and a name better then of
sons and of daughters. I will give them
an everlasting name that shall not be
cut off. also the sons of the stranger
that join themselves to the Lord to
serve him and to love the name of the
Lord to be his servants everyone that
keepeth the Sabbath from polluting it
and taking hold of my covenant.
>> Even them will I bring to my holy mount
and make them joyful in mine house of
prayer. Their burnt offerings and their
sacrifices shall be accepted upon my
altar. For mine house shall be called an
house of prayer for all people.
>> That's that's all I got on it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Jerome, because like you say
in the scripture, Saturday has seven on
it and Sunday has one.
>> That's the first day of the week. So
it's a big difference in one and seven.
Yep. Thank you for that brother. Hope
that answered their question. As we move
on,
>> moving on. Shanquil Au jobi asks in
James 1 vers 6 and 7, if you pray and
still feel sadness throughout the day,
does that mean you lack faith and your
prayer won't be answered? If so, how can
one truly have faith with be with
feeling those emotions?
>> All right, question about faith. James
1,
James 1 and read that verse 6 and 7. And
the guest caller will take it there
asking about faith and emotions.
>> Okay. James 1 6 and 7 says, "But let him
ask in faith, nothing wavering, for he
that waverth is like a wave of the sea
driven with the wind and tossed. For let
not that man think that he shall receive
anything of the Lord."
>> Well, the worst thing is he talking
about wavering. That's talking about you
were asking, but you really don't
believe. See, sadness have nothing to do
with faith unless you don't believe what
the Lord will that the Lord will hear
you before you ask. And the Lord made a
clear statement here. Let's go to and
read Mark 11. Go to Mark the 11th
chapter and read verse 24.
Mark 11 and verse 24
says,
"Therefore I say unto you, what things
soever ye desire when ye pray, believe
that ye receive them, and ye shall have
them."
>> Now, that's a direct a direct promise
from Jesus.
Now, if you are sad because you don't
believe that he's going to do it, then
of course then you ain't got no faith.
But if you're sad for some other reason,
but you believe he going to hear his his
prayer, then that's hear your prayer,
then that's different. You know, it's uh
I go back to Shadrach, Meshach, and
Abedneo.
when Nebuchadnezzar to ask them, you
know, when I when the music blow, you
going uh uh uh you supposed to fall down
on your face. They said, "Look,
we know that our God can deliver us
whether he will or not that we don't
know. But it's one thing we do know.
We ain't bowing down to that stature.
So you know that the Lord can hear your
prayer
and deliver.
Whether he will or not, you don't know.
But if you got it in your mind that he
will do it, then he will do it because
he said it right there in Mark the 11th
chapter.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Tanya Ligins want explanation
on how Sunday Christians are worshiping
another Jesus.
>> All right, Sunday Christians, how are
they worshiping another Jesus? Brother
Dre,
>> let's go over to second Corinthians the
11th chapter and pick it up at verse
two. Read verses 2 through 4 and then we
going to skip.
Okay, that's 2 Corinthians the 11th
chapter
>> verses 2-4. Correct?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Okay. It says, "For I am jealous over
you with godly jealousy, for I have
espoused you to one husband that I may
present you as a chasteed virgin to
Christ."
But I fear least by any means as the
serpent begoued Eve through his
subility, so your mind should be
corrupted from the simplicity that is in
Christ.
For if he that cometh preacheth another
Jesus, whom we have not preached, or if
ye receive another spirit, which ye have
not received, or another gospel which ye
have not accepted, ye might well bear
with him. Now,
just like the serpent begaled Eve in the
garden through subility, he didn't come
as Satan the devil. He appeared as an
angel of light. And she looked at the
tree like it was good for food and
pleasant to the eyes and a tree to be
desired to make one wise. And she took
of that fruit. Here's the thing. The
question is, how are they worshiping
another Jesus?
First of all, they not worshiping him on
the day that he set aside for him to
worship. But we going to continue to
read. Skip down to verse 13 and read
through 15.
>> Okay.
>> It says, "For such are false apostles,
deceitful workers, transforming
themselves into the apostles of Christ,
>> and no marvel, for Satan himself is
transformed into an angel of light.
Therefore, it is no great thing if he
ministers also if his ministers also be
transformed as the ministers of
righteousness whose end shall be
according to their works.
>> And notice here he says that Satan is
transformed into an angel of light. And
he said, "These that are coming to you,
they are false apostles, deceitful
workers, and they transform themselves
into the apostles of Christ." And he
said, "Therein end shall be according to
their works." Now, what is it that some
of them do that we know that they
worshiping another Jesus? In Luke 4 and
16, Jesus custom was to go into the
synagogue on the Sabbath day.
The ones that worship another's Jesus is
custom to go in to church on the first
day of the week. The Sabbath day is the
seventh day. The first day of the week
is not the Sabbath day. Jesus said in
Matthew 5 and5, "Blessed are the meek,
for they shall inherit the earth." Those
that worship another Jesus think they
going to live in heaven.
If you say the Lord's Prayer, the Lord's
Prayer says, "Our Father, which art in
heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy
kingdom come, thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven." That mean his
kingdom is coming and his will going to
be done on earth as it is in heaven.
Those that worship another Jesus think
they are going to live in heaven.
John 14 and 15 says, "If you love me,
keep my commandments." They tell you,
"You don't have to keep no law." But let
me show you one more thing. What Jesus
said,
and we quoted John 14 and 15, is Jesus
saying, "If you love me, keep my
commandments." The other Jesus
worshippers tell you you don't have to
keep them.
Let's go to Luke 6 and we just going to
read 46 and that'll be it. Luke 6 and
46.
>> Okay.
>> Luke 6 and 46 says, "And why call ye me
Lord? Lord, and do not the things which
I say." So all these people giving you
that lip service, they are doing just
the opposite of what Jesus did, but yet
they call themselves Christians.
Some of them in ignorance, some of them
knowing what they're doing,
but that is the difference. And the
other Jesus is the false one. That these
worshippers come in his name, but they
riding right behind Satan, the devil,
appearing as servants of God. That's all
I got.
>> Can I throw in a couple?
>> Yes, sir. Guess call.
>> First thing is, let's see how long
[clears throat] Jesus been around. read
first Corinthians 10th uh chapter and
and and let's see how long Jesus been
around and in the meantime while you
reading that somebody can find where
it's written. He said it's a a Sabbath
is a sign between me and my people and
then
>> Exodus 31.
>> Okay. And the other one Jesus say I'm
the God lord also of the Sabbath day.
Somebody find that in a new book. Let's
go into first Corinthians the 10th
chapter. Let these people know who they
dealing with. Start at verse one, 1 to
5. 1 Corinthians 10:es 1-5 says,
"Moreover, brethren, I would not that ye
should be ignorant how that all our
fathers were under the cloud, and all
passed through the sea, and were all
baptized unto Moses in the cloud and in
the sea, and did eat all the same
spiritual meat, and did all drink the
same spiritual drink. For they drank of
that spiritual rock that followed them.
And that rock was Christ.
>> But with
>> who was back there? Who was the back
there with Moses there?
>> Christ.
>> Jesus.
>> There you go. Now read what? So now, so
the one that told Israel then as a
Sabbath day sign between me and you.
Somebody read that.
>> That's Exodus 31 and 17. It says,
"It is a sign between me and the
children of Israel forever. For in six
days the Lord made heaven and earth, and
on the seventh day he rested and was
refreshed."
>> Now he said him and the children of
Israel. Didn't
>> y
>> Now the new book he said he is lord of
what? Somebody read that.
>> Somebody find it right quick and read
it.
Matthew 12:8 I think said
>> yeah Matthew 12 and8 says
>> okay
>> Matthew 12
and verse 8 says
for the son of man is Lord even of the
Sabbath day.
So now he says a sign between him and
Israel and that was him Jesus dealing
with Israel. Then he turned around and
said that he is Lord of the Sabbath day.
So who is Lord of Sunday? Ask yourself
that question. That's all I got to say.
>> All right. Thank you for that add-on.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
>> Uh yes, Malinka Bank is adding on to her
previous question asked. She says, "Now,
for those who were once in the truth,
but have turned to other teachings,
should I keep trying to bring them back
or leave it alone and focus on my own
salvation?"
>> All right. Well, if they didn't walked
away from the truth, sometimes people no
have no longer have that ear to even
want to hear the truth. But let's go
into Titus 3. Titus the third chapter.
Because sometime people make a choice to
walk away and not much you can do about
that.
>> Okay.
>> Titus 3 and let's pick it up. Uh read
verse 10
and 11 for me. Go ahead.
>> Okay. A man that is an heretic after the
first and second admonition reject
knowing that he that is such is
subverted and sinnth being condemned of
himself. So when you walk away from the
truth and you trying to bring them back
after you go to them after the first or
the second time trying to show them the
way or and they don't receive it then
you just have to leave it alone knowing
that he that such is subverted. He
didn't walked away on his own. And if he
don't repent and come back to the light
there ain't nothing you can do.
[clears throat]
But um let's go to Matthew 7 and then we
going to go to Philippians after that.
Let's go to Matthew 7. Because if you
keep trying to push the word on them and
they not trying to receive it, you can
create a problem for yourself. Matthew 7
and let's pick it up at that verse six.
Matthew 7 and 6.
>> Okay. Matthew 7 and6 says, "Give not
that which is holy unto the dogs,
neither cast ye your pearls before
swine, least they trample them under
their feet, and turn again and rend
you."
>> So the word of God is that pearl, and if
you keep trying to put those pearls on
them, and they don't want to head,
they'll turn around and they will turn
on you. So turn to Philippians 2.
Philippians the 2 chapter.
And when you get there, brother,
Philippians 2 and pick it up at that
verse
12 for me because you act as asked about
working out your own salvation. Let's
see what it say in verse 12. Go ahead.
Wherefore, my beloved, as ye have always
obeyed, not as in my presence only, but
now much more in my absence, work out
your own salvation with fear and
trembling.
>> Cuz time is short. And if you do that,
verse 15, go ahead. that ye may be
blameless and harmless, the sons of God,
without rebuke in the midst of a crooked
and perverse nation, among whom ye shine
as lights in the world.
>> So you keep your light shining and
burning bright and um
God will deliver in the end. That's all
I got.
But again too, it says in Hebrews that
once you had tasted the good word
on they say and turn away from it, it is
impossible.
>> Turn them back. Somebody find that right
quick.
>> Hebrews 6.
>> Yeah.
>> Hebrews 6 and4.
>> Okay.
>> Read that. That's some scary stuff, but
that's the way it is. Read it. Hebrews
6:4 says, "For it is impossible for
those who were once enlightened and have
tasted of the heavenly gift and were
made partakers of the Holy Ghost and
have tasted the good word of God and the
powers of the world to come. if if they
shall fall away to renew them again unto
repentance, seeing they crucify to
themselves the son of God aresh and put
to him an open shame.
>> So now you wasting your time. The book
says impossible. If they really had some
understanding was in this thing and then
they turned away from it, then how you
going what you going to tell them to get
them back in it?
>> Uh-uh. You're wasting your time.
>> Yep.
All right, thank you for that add-on.
Hope that answers your question. As we
move on to our next
>> moving on, Bobby Turner says, "Since
they are grafted into the body and the
same as the original Israelites,
can Gentiles serve as head
on any IOG committee? example welcoming
or feast or etera
>> right Gentiles are grafted in can they
serve in any of the lead positions guest
caller
>> you know somebody have a problem paying
attention to what's written in the book
I go to Deuteronomy the 17th chapter and
read verse 15
Okay.
The 17th chapter and verse 15. Correct,
sir.
>> That's correct.
>> Okay. It says, "Thou shalt in any wise
set him king over thee, whom the Lord
thy God shall choose. One from among thy
brethren shalt thou set king over thee.
Thou mayest not set a stranger over
thee, which is not thy brother.
>> Now look, what if this king was a
spiritual Israelite? It didn't say
nothing about that, did it?
>> Nope.
>> Let's go and let's figure let's go and
see what the Lord said
he want he was going to who going to
represent him. Go to Isaiah the 43rd
chapter. Read verse 1
7 10 and 21.
>> Okay. One Isaiah 43 verse1
says, "But now thus sayeth the Lord,
that created thee, oh Jacob, and he that
formed thee, O Israel, fear not, for I
have redeemed thee. I have called thee
by thy name. Thou art mine."
>> Uhhuh. Verse 7 says, "Even everyone that
is called by my name, for I have created
him for my glory. I have formed him.
Yay, I have made him."
>> He said, "Now I've created him for my
glory." He didn't say nothing about
spiritual, did he?
>> No.
>> Skip down to verse 10 and read it.
It says, "Ye are my witnesses, saeth the
Lord, and my servant whom I have chosen,
that ye may know and believe me, and
understand that I am he. Before me there
was no God formed, neither shall there
be after me."
>> So he said, "Israel is his witnesses."
Ain't that right? Ain't that who he was
talking to?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Skip down to verse 21 and read it.
It says this people have I formed for
myself. They shall show
>> this people this people who have been
converted into mine.
>> No,
>> I have formed for myself.
>> This people have I formed for myself.
They shall show forth my praise.
Who shall
>> they shall show forth my praise?
>> Had nothing to do with a converted
anybody. Now let's go to Romans the 9th
chapter and read verses 1-5.
>> Okay.
Romans the 9th chapter verses 1-5.
It says,
"I say the truth in Christ, I lie not,
my conscience also bearing me witness in
the Holy Ghost, that I have great
heaviness and continual sorrow in my
heart. For I could wish that myself were
a curse from Christ for my brethren, my
kinsmen according to the flesh, who are
Israelites, to whom pertainth the
adoption
>> and the adoption.
>> And what?
>> And the glory.
>> And the glory. And what?
>> And the covenants.
>> And the co and what?
>> And the giving of the law.
>> And what? and the service of God.
>> Finish it.
>> And the promises.
>> So, where's anybody else?
Now, this is a new book. This is Paul,
the apostle to the Gentiles.
Go to one last place.
St. John 14, uh, chapter 4, read 19- 22.
>> Okay. John 4:1 19-22
says, "The woman saying unto him," Sir,
I perceive that thou art a prophet, our
fathers worshiped in this mountain, and
ye say that in Jerusalem is the place
where men ought to worship."
Jesus saith unto her,"Woman,
believe me, the hour cometh, when ye
shall neither in this mountain, nor yet
at Jerusalem worship the Father. Ye
worship, ye know not what we know what
we worship, for salvation is of the
Jews."
Now, you know, we we are uh uh uh we
have a lot of strangers, Gentiles and
other people too, Amitesites, that are
part of the Israeli God.
But just like you saw in the wilderness,
you had a mixed multitude.
But we saw but we didn't see no
non-Israelite
placed over any of the Hebrews
under no circumstances.
Work on the team good.
Be a part of it good.
But to be over Israelites ain't nowhere
in the book we see that
it got nothing to do with spiritual
Israel. has got something to do to put
with protocol and God set it up. Point
blank. The answer is no. That's all I
have to say.
>> All right, we're going to leave it right
there as we move on to our next
question.
>> Next one. Sky Ryder asks, "Does each
trumpet really brings each vow of wrath
or does the last trumpet bring seven
vows of wrath?" And they give revelation
11 verse 18 and state the time of your
wrath has come. Then later in revelation
16 talk about the pouring of the wrath.
And then uh they give for example
revelation 8
and 9 the third trumpet onethird sea
life dies.
But in Revelation 16:3
vows of wrath, everything in the sea
dies. So the question is, does each
trumpet really bring each bowl of wrath
uh does each trumpet brings
each vow of wrath or does the last
trumpet bring seven vows of wrath?
>> All right. Yeah, brother Jerome, I see
where they wrote bold, but we know it
mean viol and they had their three
scripture over what we require. But go
ahead, brother.
>> I I'd like to uh answer this question,
but I need to separate
um separate into three parts. Okay. Um
the first part I want to deal with
is when you mention does each trumpet
really bring
each vial which you got bowl of wrath or
does the last trumpet bring seven
bowls or vials of wrath. Let's let's
read Revelations the 15th chapter verse
7.
Okay. Revelation 15:7
says,
"And one of the four beasts gave unto
the seven angels,
seven golden vials full of the wrath of
God, who liveth forever and ever." Okay,
so it mentioned is seven vials
full of the wrath of God. Now,
that's talking about in the vials, but
don't confuse that with the wrath that
you read about uh under the sixth seal.
Let me show you what I mean. Let's go to
Revelations chapter 6.
>> Okay?
>> Cuz during this whole tribulation, it's
going to be plenty wrath going on. But
you got some wrath that's dealing with
some virals. But you got some other
wrath. And I'm going to show you an
example of that. And the Lord is
mustering it up. Okay. So now,
Revelation 6,
pick it up at the verse 12. Just read
verse 12.
It says, "And I beheld, when he had
opened the sixth seal, and lo, there was
a great earthquake, and the sun became
black as sapcloth of hair, and the moon
became as blood." Skip down and read
verse 15-1 17.
and the kings of the earth, and the
great men, and the rich men, and the
chief captains, and the mighty men, and
every bond man, and every free man hid
themselves in the dens, and in the rocks
of the mountains, and said to the
mountains and rocks, fall on us, and
hide us from the face of him that siteth
on the throne, and from the wrath of the
Lamb.
For the great day of his wrath is come
and who shall be able to stand.
>> You can read where this is happening.
You can read where this is happening
during the sixth seal. And you have to
understand the chronological order. You
got seven seals all together.
Okay? All of them seals got to be opened
before you even get to trumpets
or vials.
Okay? So now you reading about some
wrath happening right right around the
sixth seal. Okay, that's before you even
get to the trumpets of the vials. But
then you got some wrath that's
associated with the vials.
And the trumpet announcing you got the
first trumpet that's going to announce
the plagues that's in the first vial.
You got the second trumpet announcing
the plagues that's in the second vow. So
it they announce it, okay? And so on
through all the seven trumpets and all
the seven vows, the trumpets announce
the plagues that's in the vials. Okay?
So now you got on here also your second
part of the question. You got
Revelations 11 and 18.
Let's read that.
>> Okay. Revelation 11:18 says, "And the
nations were angry, and thy wrath has
come, and the time of the dead, that
they should be judged, that thou
shouldest give reward unto thy servants,
the prophets, and to the saints, and
them that fear thy name, small and
great, and should shouldest destroy
them, which destroy the earth."
>> All right. So it said the Lord's wrath
has come. We read what the Lord's wrath
had started already. And guess what
happened? The stars fell from heaven. It
said the stars fell out from from uh the
heavens rolled back like a scroll and
the stars fell down from to this earth.
That's what it said. Okay. But that
ain't got nothing to do with the wrath
that's in them vials.
Okay. So now uh you also had Revelations
verse three.
Read that.
It says, "And the second angel poured
out his vial upon the sea, and it became
as the blood of a dead man, and every
living soul died in the sea." So you was
connecting that with that Revelations 8
that's in your question. Revelations 8
verse 8 and 9. So read that cuz that's
the trumpet that's announcing the vow
that was mentioned in Revelation 16 and
3. So read that. Revelations 8:9.
It says, "And the second angel sounded,
and as it were, a great mountain burning
with fire was cast into the sea, and the
third part of the sea became blood, and
the third part of the creatures which
were in the sea and had life died,
>> and the third part of the ships were
destroyed."
So you was making a point where when it
announced it in the trumpet, it talked
about a third part of this and a third
part of that. But then when you got to
Revelation 16 and3, it said everything,
all the uh uh uh uh uh that dwelt in the
sea, you know, like the fishes or
whatever. It said all of them. Look,
all of them didn't die. Okay? It said a
third part. All right. Now, the reason
why I know it ain't all cuz I'm getting
ready to tie you to this Ezekiel and let
you know it's still some it's still
going to be some fish in the sea and
people going to be throwing out their uh
nets fishing.
>> Okay. You know,
>> can I intervene?
>> There's a simpler way of saying that. He
taking the whole thing around. Can I Can
I Can I throw in a simple way?
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Go to Revelation 7 chapter and start
reading at verse one.
>> Okay.
Revelation 7 and verse one says,
"And after these things I saw four
angels standing on the four corners of
the earth, holding the four winds of the
earth, that the wind should not blow on
the earth, nor on the sea, nor on any
tree."
And I saw another And I saw another
angel ascending from the east, having
the seal of the living God. And he cried
with a loud voice to the four angels to
whom it was given to hurt the earth and
the sea, saying, "Hurt not the earth,
neither the sea, nor the trees, till we
have sealed the servants of our God in
their foreheads."
And then he sealed 144,000
Israel and then a number that no man
could number. Now what he did before
the Lord start poured out his wrath
beast and false prophet they had done
some wrath too. So the difference is the
seven trumpets
called the Lord's seven vows of wrath.
But the rap before that he allowed it
happen by the hands of the beast and
prophet.
>> So the simple thing is
God separated his servant
before he start and put his seal on him
before he start pouring out his ram.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. And as far as the third part is
it's talking about the third part of
this and the third part of that. All the
fish in that third part is what died not
the whole sea.
So the brother was going right to go to
Ezekiel to let you know there's going to
be a whole lot of fish left when the
Lord come. But he was talking about the
third part. That part that was ruled by
the beast and false prophet. The rese
false prophet did their wrath. Jesus
sealed his servants. Then he poured out
his wrath.
>> Which is the seven pl seven last plagues
which is poured out before uh uh uh uh
you know you know by Jesus. Trumpets
don't bring no wrath. Trumpets announce.
>> You blow the trumpet something happen.
Blow it again something else happen.
blow it again, something else happen.
And on the seventh trumpet, when you
blow it, then that brings the Lord.
>> That's the biggest wrath because he said
that he going to fill the place with
dead body. That's all I have to say. I
think it's a little simple.
>> All right. One is the
>> prophet and the other the trumpets and
the and the and the vows of ramp is the
wrath of Jesus
>> that he poured out on nonbelievers,
not his servants.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answers your question as we continue to
move on.
>> Moving on. Michael Crawl says, "I need a
scripture so I can understand. Can we
use a microwave on the Sabbath? A
brother on another show said it was okay
since it's not fire.
>> All right. Well, a brother on another
show that said you can use the microwave
since it's not fire is incorrect. You
cannot use the microwave on the Sabbath
day. And me and brother Julius, we've
always talked about how the last word,
last name of a microwave is oven. Right,
Julius?
>> Right, brother?
>> So, we got a microwave oven. Then me and
Dre have had the discussion about you
can put certain things in a microwave. I
know if you put metal or aluminum in
there, it would catch fire, won't it?
>> Yeah. And if you leave any type
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yeah. And if you if you leave any type
of food in there too long, it will burn.
So, no, you can't use the microwave. But
let's go to Exodus 35. Exodus 35 and
let's pick it up. Let's read that verse
uh two and I believe three because this
will cover, you know, the um crockpotss.
We get all different ways of people
trying to ease in something that cannot
be used on the Sabbath. We appreciate
your question. We just here to correct
it where it needs correcting at uh
Exodus 35 and let's read verse two and
three. Go ahead, brother.
>> It says, "Six days shall work be done.
But on the seventh day, there shall be
to you an holy day, a Sabbath of rest.
Whosoever doeth work therein shall be
put to death."
>> Yep. So Lord makes that simple. But here
we go now. This is the microwave and the
crock pot and the electric pots and all
these different things that they use.
Verse three.
>> Ye shall kindle no fire throughout your
habitations
upon the Sabbath day.
>> So microwave falls under kindling of
fire
on the Lord's Sabbath day. So, no using
your microwave on the Sabbath. And
that's all I got.
>> Unplug it.
>> Yep. Unplug it. Even your crop,
>> they can't do nothing. They can't do
nothing if you unplug it.
>> That's right. Crockpot as well. People
trying to leave that still cooking while
they going to honor the Sabbath. No.
Make sure you turn it off. All right.
Let's move on to our next question,
sister.
>> Next question. Mr. incredible asks, "If
a woman divorces a man, will the man be
committing adultery if he were to
remarry?"
>> All right, guess caller.
>> Deuteronomy 24, read verse 1 and two.
>> Deuteronomy 24.
One and two.
>> Okay. Deuteronomy 24:es
1 and 2 says, "When a man hath taken a
wife and married her, and it come to
pass that she find no favor in his eyes,
because he hath found some uncleanness
in her, then let him write her a bill of
divorcement, and give it in her hand,
and send her out of his house." and when
she is departed out of his house, she
may go and be another man's wife.
>> Well, I'm pretty sure this if she can be
another man's wife, he can be another
woman's husband.
Let's go into 1 Corinthians 7, read
verse 10 through 15.
>> Okay. 1 Corinthians 7 10-
15 says, "And unto the married I
command, yet not I, but the Lord. Let
not the wife depart from her husband,
but and if she depart, let her remain
unmarried, or be reconciled to her
husband, and let not the husband put
away his wife."
But to the rest speak, I, not the Lord.
If any brother hath a wife that
believeth not, and she be pleased to
dwell with him, let him not put her
away. And the woman which hath an
husband that believeth not. And if he be
pleased to dwell with her, let her not
leave him. For the unbelieving husband
is sanctified by the wife, and the
unbelieving wife is sanctified by the
husband. Else were your children
unclean, but now are they holy.
But if the unbelieving depart, let him
depart. A brother or a sister is not
under bondage in such cases, but God
hath called us to peace. Mhm.
>> That's the best I can give you.
>> All I have to say.
>> All right, we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Next one. Zion asks, "Can the word fruit
in the Bible also be someone's words,
knowledge, or their or or your works."
And then they asked about a tree. Also
the word tree, can it also be a person?
>> Right. So, brother Julius, the word
fruit, can it be words, knowledge or
works? And what about tree? Can that
also be a person?
>> Yes. Yes. Yes. And yes.
Matthew the 7th chapter.
Metaphorically met. There are physical
trees that grow out the ground. And then
Satan the devil is a corrupt tree. And
what Jesus is trying to make us is trees
of righteousness
and fruits is your your works also.
Matthew se uh 7 and begin reading at
verse uh
[clears throat]
verse 15. Go ahead. Matthew 7:15. Come
on James. Beware of the false prophets,
which come to you in sheep's clothing,
but inwardly they are ravening wolves.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Ye shall know them by their fruits.
>> Oh, you shall know them by their works,
their behaviors. Go ahead.
>> Do men gather grapes of thorns or figs
of thistles?
>> Go ahead.
>> Even so, every good tree bringeth forth
good fruit.
>> This This Jesus is the tree of life.
That's manifestally speaking. And he
came and did a great work. A became a
sin offering and a sacrifice and to
kickstart his priest. That's a great
work. Go ahead.
>> But a corrupt tree bringeth forth evil
fruit.
>> That's Satan the devil. One hiding
behind one tree in the midst. Isaiah 66
tell you this is Satan the devil. He's
that tree uh of the knowledge of good
and evil. He's wicked. Go ahead. A good
tree cannot bring forth evil fruit.
>> Neither neither can a corrupt tree bring
forth good fruit.
>> Go ahead.
>> Every tree that bringeth not forth good
fruit is heuned down and cast into the
fire.
>> Yes. Satan and his angels and everybody
that follow him. Especially if you take
that mark going into the lake of fire.
Go ahead. Cuz you listen to the wrong
tree. Go ahead. Wherefore by their
fruits ye shall know them.
>> The Bible has answered that question
without a shadow of a doubt. So the
answer is yes. Yes. Yes. And yes. That's
all I got.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on with a time
check.
>> Yes. Uh the time is 8:30 and moving on.
be alert as can you can you please
explain Jeremiah 1 verse 12 the
significance of the almond tree
>> Jeremiah 1 and12 let's go there James
and then the guest caller will shed some
light on the significance of the almond
tree
>> okay Jeremiah 1 and 12 says then said
the Lord unto me thou hast well seen for
I will hasten my word to perform it.
>> Wait a minute.
>> But the omry was actually in verse 11.
>> Read 11.
>> Yeah.
>> Moreover, the word of the Lord came unto
me, saying, Jeremiah, what seeest thou?
And I said, I see a rod of an almond
tree.
a rod or a staff or either a stick
that was made from an almond tree.
That's all. Just like I can get an oak
tree and make you a rod or a staff out
of it,
a pine tree.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Says made a rod or a staff, you know, or
a walking stick out of a almond tree.
>> Simple as that. what it says.
>> All right. The material where the stick
came from.
>> All right. I hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Be alert again as this time is
into three questions. Be alert as when
Jesus returns will he be the light of
the world? Will there be no more moon
and sun in Jesus kingdom?
And will the saints of the first
resurrection be light to the world also?
>> All right, brother Jerome, what you say?
>> Yeah. Jesus, he he the light of the
world right now. right now
>> through through through the word that
shine shine his light to to lighten
every man that cometh into the world.
Whether they take heed of that light or
not, it's it's up to them. But uh go to
uh St. John chapter 8 verse 12.
Okay. John 8 verse 12 says, "Then spake
Jesus again unto them, saying, I am the
light of the world. He that followeth me
shall not walk in darkness."
>> Yeah.
>> But shall have the light of life.
>> Let's tie us with uh Isaiah 8 and 20.
Okay.
Isaiah 8 and 20 says
to the law and to the testimony. If they
speak not according to this word, it is
because there is no light in them.
>> Yeah.
In short is the word of God. Okay. So
now your second you had a another
question about the sun and the moon. So
Deborah, can you read that part again?
>> Will there be no more moon and sun in
Jesus kingdom?
>> Uh yeah, there there'll still be uh sun
and a moon in Lord's kingdom. Uh let
let's go to Genesis 8:22
and then we going to go to Revelations
after that.
>> Okay.
Genesis 8 and 22
it says
while the earth remainth seed time and
harvest and cold and heat and summer and
winter and day and night shall not
cease.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. And go to Revelations 14, read
verse 10 and 11.
Revelation 14 10 and 11 say,
"The same shall drink of the wine of the
wrath of God, which is poured out
without mixture into the cup of Oh, I'm
sorry. Hold on.
Revelation, you said Revelation."
>> Yeah. 10 through 11. Cuz he gonna say
something in the verse that's got
something to do with day and night.
>> Okay. And that's 14, correct?
>> Yeah. Revelation 14 verse 11
>> it says the same shall drink of the wine
of the wrath of God which is poured out
without mixture into the cup of his
indignation and he shall be tormented
with fire and brimstone in the presence
of the holy angels and in the presence
of the lamb
>> and the smoke of their tormented
ascendeth up forever and ever and they
have no rest day nor a night who worship
the beast beast in his image and
whosoever receiveth the mark of his
name.
>> Yeah, it's one other place, but I'm
going to deal with that that last part
of your question. But for your notes,
also write down Isaiah 65
verse 20- 23 about that moon, sun and
the moon part of your question. Now
read that letter part of the question
for me, Deborah.
All right, the last part was, "Will the
saints of the first resurrection be
light to the world also?"
>> And the answer is, "Yeah, they they
lights to the world right now that carry
his word and truth and they walking in
it." Yeah, they light to the world, too.
So, let's uh right now. Okay. So, read
Matthew's chapter 5 verse 14- 16.
>> Okay.
Matthew chapter 5
vers 14. You said 14- 16, correct?
>> Yeah.
>> It says, "Ye are the light of the world.
A city that is set on an hill cannot be
hid.
Neither do men light a candle and put it
under a bushel, but on a candlestick,
and it giveth light unto all that are in
the house. Let your light so shine
before men that they may see your good
works and glorify your father which is
in heaven.
>> Yeah, that's it. That's all I got.
>> All right,
thank you for that. As we move on to our
next question,
>> next one. Anan twin Israel says in
Jeremiah 35 it mentions the house of the
recabites and their obedience with their
fathers commanding his sons to drink no
wine build houses and they shall dwell
in tents. They want explanation on
verses 5 through 7 and 18 and 19. And
then they ask, "Are the recites
still around?"
>> All right. Jeremiah 35
verse 5-7 first and then 18-19. Guest
caller would take it from there.
>> Okay. Jeremiah 35:E5
says, "And I set before the sons of the
house of the Recoites plots full of wine
and cups, and I said unto them, drink ye
wine." But they said, "We will not
drink. We will drink no wine. For
Jonadab, the son of Richab, our father,
commanded us, saying, Ye shall drink no
wine. Neither ye nor your sons forever.
Neither shall ye build house now mean
nor seow seed nor plant vineyard nor
have any but all your days ye shall
dwell in tents that ye may live many
days in the land where ye be strangers
>> but verse you just got to read
>> that was verse seven sir uh Jeremiah 35
and 7
>> read verse 18 and
It says, "And Jeremiah said unto the
house of the Recabites, thus said the
Lord of hosts, the God of Israel,
because ye have obeyed the commandment
of Jonadab your father, and kept all his
precepts, and done according unto all
that he hath commanded you. Therefore,
thus sayeth the Lord of hosts, the God
of Israel, Jonadab, the son of Recob,
shall not want a man to stand before me
forever.
>> Now, the question was, are there retites
still around?
The 19th verse answer that question.
Read it again.
Therefore, thus sayeth the Lord of
hosts, the God of Israel, Jonadab, the
son of Reab, shall not want a man to
stand before me forever.
So that mean that somebody's around
standing before the Lord in every
generation say he shall not want a man.
In other words, he can always have
somebody standing before him. That's in
every generation. 19 voice a voice
answer the question and the question and
the answer to the question is yeah
it's still around
>> all right thank you for that hope that
answers your question next question
>> uh yes this question I'm getting ready
to ask uh was already answered but Bran
64 asks will the seven seals all take
place during the great tribulation and
are the seven trumpets and the seven
vows corresponded with each other.
>> All right, brother Jerome.
>> Yeah, it said the seven seals take place
during the great tribulation. That's
that's a yes. Okay, because the great
tribulation actually start with the
first seal that you read about in
Revelations the sixth chapter. That's
when it start and
the seven trumpets and the seven vials,
they do correlate with each other
because the trumpets announce
the the plagues that's in the seven
vials. They announce it. You get the
first trumpet, it blow, and then it
announce the plague of the first vial
and so on so forth for all the rest of
the trumpets and vows. That's all I got.
>> All right,
our next question.
>> Yes, moving on. Diane Miller wants you
to explain Deuteronomy 14 verse 21.
>> Deuteronomy 14 and 21. Let's go there.
Number 14 and 21
because this is dealing with Israel
and then it's dealing with the stranger
or in this verse the alien and we
talking about food here clean food.
Go ahead brother.
Deuteronomy 14:21 says, "Ye shall not
eat of anything that dieth of itself.
Thou shalt give it unto the stranger
that is in thy gates, that he may eat
it, or thou mayest sell it unto an
alien. For thou art an holy people unto
the Lord thy God. Thou shalt not see a
kid in his mother's milk."
>> All right. So, it's talking about you
shall not eat of anything that dieth of
itself. You have some an animal that you
may have and it just so happened to die,
then you weren't allowed to eat that.
But you could sell it to the stranger as
well as to the alien.
So, we're talking about clean food, of
course. We're not talking about anything
other than the food that we hear that's
in the Lord's dietary law. That was all
that you were allowed to eat. That's all
I got. Anybody else?
All right, we're going to keep it
moving.
>> Moving on. Melon Natural Journey asks,
"Is it true that everyone has an angel
and a demer demon watching them 24 hours
a day? Every day."
>> All right. Who's watching you 24 hours a
day, Julius? Every day. Let's find out
uh uh there was war in heaven revelation
the 12th chapter and Satan and his
angels lost that onethird of a new
amount innumerable amount of angels is
down here on this earth fallen angels so
now let's go to Hebrews the first
chapter
we let the book answer that questions
chapter 1 James and pick it up at verse
It says, "And of the angels he saith,
who maketh his angels spirits, and his
ministers a flame of fire."
>> So these angels are ministers,
all of them. Skip down to verse 14.
It says,
"Are they not all ministering spirits
sent forth to minister for them who
shall be heirs of salvation?"
>> So now, let's go to uh
Psalm 34.
Remember, got a whole bunch of angels
down here. And you got them righteous
angels down here. Sisters and brothers,
angels
are
created beings. They sent to protect,
they lead, they guide, they can deceive,
they minister, and they can destroy.
You're like, that's going on all the
time.
>> Yep.
>> So, go to uh what is what did I say? Uh
Psalm 34.
>> Psalm 34. Correct.
>> What do verse 7 say, James?
The angel of the Lord encampeth round
about them that fear him and deliverth
them.
>> Long as you fearing the Lord, the Lord
got that angel around you. If you keep
his commandments, he got that angel
around you.
>> But guess who else is looking observing?
Let's go to first Peter 5 and read verse
eight.
>> Okay,
>> remember what we read in Job the first
the second chapters. Job the first
chapter. Them angels came to give a
report, didn't they?
>> Yes, they did.
>> Finish read that. Finish reading the
verse in Psalm first. They didn't finish
it. He camping around them to do what?
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> Do it again. Do it again, James.
>> Okay, hold on one second here. Psalm 34
>> and seven. And seven says, "The angel of
the Lord encampeth round about them that
fear him and deliverth them."
>> To do what?
>> Okay.
>> And delivereth them.
>> Okay. To make, in other words, he's
protecting you.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So now go to First Peter 5 and 8. And
that'll be it.
1 Peter 5:8 says, "Be sober, be
viligent,
>> because your adversary the devil as a
roaring lion walketh about seeking whom
he may devour."
>> That's right. So if he here and remember
he got kicked out and a third part of
the angels of heaven that that that he
persuaded one-third of an innumerable
amount of angels. So that's why Paul
told you we wrestle not against flesh
and blood against spiritual wickedness
in high places. They are here sisters
and brothers.
>> That's all I got.
>> Like like you were saying, brother
Julius, you put on that whole armor of
God that will help you to fight that
evil angel.
>> You depart from the Lord. Go back and
look what happened to uh Saul. An evil
angel from the Lord came upon him and
chased him to his to his death.
>> Yep. All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Bobby Turner says, "If you use
a thermos that keeps your coffee hot for
36 hours,
isn't that the same as kindling a fire?
Isn't that the same as putting hot water
in noodles and allowing them to cook,
which we can't do?"
All right, brother Dre, share some
light.
>> No, it's not the same. If you do it on
the sixth day, you are good. It keeps it
hot for 36 hours.
>> And you do on the sixth day, you put it
in there and it's if it's going to keep
it hot, you got it hot. If you put your
noodles in there on the sixth day, it is
hot because it keeps it hot for 36
hours. long as it's not a plugin
uh thermos and it's just a thermos that
keeps it hot. You prepare on the sixth
day. Exodus 35 and we going to read that
again. Let's just go there. Exodus 35
1:3. Go ahead, brother James. Exodus
35:es
1 and3 says,
"And Moses gathered all the congregation
of the children of Israel together, and
said unto them, these are the words
which the Lord hath commanded that ye
should do them."
>> Do them. This is what you do. The Lord
commanded this. Go ahead.
Sixth day shall work be done, but on the
seventh day there shall be to you an
holy day, a Sabbath of rest to the Lord.
Whosoever doeth work therein shall be
put to death. Ye shall kindle no fire
throughout your habitations until the
Sabbath day. I think if we had that in
mind that we would be put to death if we
kindling the fire and doing work like
that, we wouldn't be so quick to even
think about doing nothing like that.
>> But unfortunately,
it's not in our face like that. Let's go
to Exodus 16 and we just going to read
one verse there.
>> Already there.
>> Exodus 16 and 23.
It says, "And he saith unto them, this
is that which the Lord has said,
tomorrow is the rest of the holy Sabbath
unto the Lord. Bake that which ye will
bake today, and seed that ye will see,
and that which remainth over layth up
for you to be kept until the morning."
This is This is all you have to do. If
you Hey, tomorrow is the Sabbath day. On
the sixth day, if you want to boil you
some noodles and you got hot water, put
the noodles in there. It's still going
to be good the next day,
but don't do it on the Sabbath. Just do
it on the sixth day.
>> Yeah.
>> Ain't nothing hard about that. That's
all I got. Hey Dre, can I can I can can
I say if we go back even just that one
verse in verse 22, it says it came to
pass that on the sixth day, they
gathered twice as much bread. And and
the thing about it is you're preparing
on that sixth day twice as much. So you
don't have to also try to do something
and just honor the Sabbath on the
seventh.
>> That's right. That's right. Hey, I make
my coffee uh before the Sabbath and I
got a thermos that keeps it warm. And so
on the Sabbath day, I got me some good
hot coffee because the thermos keeps it
hot. But I do it on the sixth day.
>> You got one that lasts 36 hours, you
need to put in in and let us know which
one that is.
>> That's all I got.
All right. Thank you, brother. It's all
about prep preparation.
All right. Moving on to our next
question.
>> Next one. Barbara Steel says, "I know in
the scriptures the giants were not made
by the sons of God that went into the
daughters of men." But does the Bible
say where the giants came from?
>> Where's the Bibles come from, Julius?
What's the uh Yeah, the Bible tell you
they came from their mom and daddy.
Let's go to Genesis chapter 6.
>> Okay.
>> Same place they came from. The same
place we come from. Genesis chapter 6.
James, we going to move quick with this.
Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Let's pay attention to what we reading,
sisters and brothers. Genesis 6 and
verse one. Then we going to skip to
four. When you get it, go ahead,
brother. And it came to pass when men
began to multiply on the face of the
earth and daughters were born unto them.
>> Multiply means to reproduce.
So they are keeping the first
commandment that God gave man. Multiply,
be fruitful, and replenish the earth.
Reproduce. Skip now to verse four.
>> There were giants in the earth in those
days.
>> Uhhuh. And also after that, when the
sons of God came in unto the daughters
of men,
and they bare children to them, the same
became mighty men which were of old, men
of renown.
>> So now it tell you that uh giant there
were giants in the earth in those days.
In what days? In the days when men be to
multiply upon the face of the earth. In
the days of Noah, sisters and brothers.
But these sons of God is separate from
the the angelic sons of God. These sons
of God are the sons of Adam and Seth.
That's why when you read Genesis chapter
5, it keep telling you all over the
whole chapter and they begat this and
they begat sons and daughters and they
begot sons and daughters. They children
was born. Now let's go to but we want to
highlight the word giants. Deuteronomy
chapter 2, my brother.
>> Deuteronomy chapter 2. And we are going
to talking about the people in those
days. Verse 10 and 11. Go ahead.
>> The emms. Well, they're in times past.
>> A people great and many. A people. A
people.
>> A people like you and I. Go ahead.
>> Great and many.
>> And what?
>> And tall. as the Anakims.
>> So big, tall, giant people. Verse 11.
What's the book call them?
>> Which also were accounted giants.
>> Uh-huh.
>> As the Anakims.
>> Yes.
>> But the Moabites called them ems.
>> So the an the Moabites called these big
tall giants uh Anakims. But they called
them they were Anakims or the sons of
Anoch. But the Moabites called them ems.
Let's go to second Samuel. David killed
Goliath,
a Philistine. Uh you know the same
Philistine that's in Genesis the 10th
chapter of the children of Ham flesh and
blood fathers.
2 Samuel 2 Samuel 21
verse1 15. Go ahead.
>> Okay. 2 Samuel 21:15
says, "Moreover, the Philistines had yet
war again with Israel, and David went
down and his servants with him and
fought against the Philistines, and
David waxed faint."
>> Go ahead.
>> And Ishb Bonab, which was of the sons of
the giant.
>> Oh, they're all a big tall Hamite.
Giant. Big tall man.
Now that's he that's
big tall giant right?
>> Yes.
>> Skip down to verse 17.
>> But Aishi the son of Zer Zerui
secured him and smoked the Philistine
and killed him.
>> So then
>> this guy got killed. This giant got
killed. You cannot kill an angel.
Verse 19 quickly. And there was again a
battle in Gob with the Philistines,
where Ehanan, the son of Jerajorum, a
Beth Leah, slew the brother of Goliath,
the Giddite, the staff of whose spear
was like a weaver's beam. So now this is
Goliath's brother. David killed Goliath.
So we got another brother that was
killed. This guy had uh six fingers on
each hand and six toes on each feet. He
got killed. Goliath's brother,
man.
Go ahead in verse 20.
>> And there was yet a battle in Gath,
where was a man of great stature that
had on every hand six fingers.
>> Yes.
>> And on every foot six toes.
>> Now, when I was born, I had six fingers
on each of my hand. Still five toes on
each feet, but six fingers cut off
because I'm a flesh and blood man. Go
ahead at verse 20. Finish that.
Four and 20 in number. And he was also
born to the giant.
>> Oh, he was born.
Give me my last verse. We're done. 22.
These four were born to the giant and
Gad
>> because they were big, tall people that
had mas and daddies.
Finish it.
>> And fell by the hand of David and by the
hand of his servants.
>> So David killed Goliath and his men
killed the other three brothers of
Goliath. Big tall men, a people great
and tall. That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that. As we
move on to our next question,
>> moving on.
Thou says, "If Israel was a slave nation
of two million people in Egypt, why do
archaeology and Egyptians records show
nothing? Does Satan clean it up?"
>> Yes, caller.
>> First thing is it wasn't 2 million.
600,000
that's less than 1 million and the other
and the other part of it is
archaeologist and Egyptian records do
show it who have asked this question
what you should do is do you some
research
that's all I have to say
>> all right our next question
>> okay the next question is
thou also asked for you to explain
numbers Numbers 31
17 and 18.
Numbers 317 and 18.
>> And um and it says to kill all the boys
but kept the young girls for yourselves.
And why? And is that command from God or
was it from Moses? Let's go to Numbers
31:17. Guess call and take it from
there.
>> Okay. Numbers 31-17
and 18 says, "Now therefore kill every
male among the little ones, and kill
every woman that hath known man by lying
with him.
But all the women children that have not
known a man by lying with him, keep
alive for yourselves."
>> Well, it mean what it say.
And yeah, God gave a commandment. Back
up
and read verses one and two. Skip down
to seven.
>> Okay. Verse one and two says, "And the
Lord spake unto Moses, saying, Avenge
the children of Israel of the
Midianites, afterward shalt thou be
gathered unto thy people."
Verse 7 says, "And they wared against
the Midianites as the Lord commanded
Moses, and they slew all the males."
That's the answer to the question.
Scripture say ex [clears throat] mean
exactly what they said. All of it. It
was from the Lord. It's all I got to
say.
>> All right, Sister Deborah, our final
question of the evening in new
territory. Yes, we are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, November
the 26, 2025.
Janquila Aul Joby asks if the head of
the household set a rule against God's
word, such as prohibiting his wife and
kids from attending church because he
doesn't believe. Do they have to follow
that?
>> All right. So, guest caller, they the
man in the house said a rule and uh he
don't want his kids to attend.
>> Yes. Caller, you still with us?
>> I'm still here.
>> Okay. Listen uh
>> the Lord say if you love me anybody more
than you love me you're not worthy of
me.
>> So now the Lord tell you to have over
convocation.
Then you go with it. If your husband
come against you I want you to read
something about the man that sold the
property. Let's go into Acts.
was that they sold the property and and
uh gave the wrong money
>> and annihas
>> five
>> and Annas and Safari
>> read it right quick and we got one place
after that somebody can find
>> which verse would you like me to start
>> one
>> I want start in verse one in the
meantime somebody be looking up this guy
that David uh uh uh uh you know that
that that David requested his wife and
the man told him he ain't going to give
David nothing.
>> Neab
read this verse and we go and read
Nabal. Go ahead.
>> Okay.
>> But a certain man named Ananas with
Safara his wife sold a possession and
kept back part of the price. his wife
also being privy to it and brought a
certain part and laid it at the apostles
feet.
But Peter said, "Ananas, why has Satan
filled thine heart to lie to the Holy
Ghost and to keep back part of the price
of the land? Whilst it remained, was it
not thine own? And after it was sold,
was it not in thine own power? Why hast
thou conceived this thing in thine
heart? Thou has not lied unto men, but
unto God.
And Ananas,
>> go ahead, read.
>> And Ananas hearing these words fell down
and gave up the ghost. And great fear
came on all them that heard these
things.
>> And the young
>> cause of it. Let's see what happened
with his wife. Go ahead.
And the young men arose, wound him up,
and carried him out, and buried him. And
it was about the space of 3 hours after
when his wife, not knowing what was
done, came in. And Peter answered unto
her, "Tell me whether ye sold the lamb
for so much." And she said, "Yay, for so
much." Then Peter said unto her, "How is
it that ye have agreed to together to
tempt the spirit of the Lord,
>> Behold, the feet of them which have
buried thy husband are at the door, and
shall carry thee out?"
Then she fell straight down. Then she
fell down straightway at his feet, and
yielded up the ghost. And the young men
came in and found her dead and carried
her forth, buried her by her husband.
>> Now, her husband was the head of the
household, wasn't it?
>> Yes, he was.
>> She jumped at the Lord, the Lord killed
him. And because she went along with her
husband, the head of the household, he
killed her.
That ain't in there for nothing. Now,
can somebody go and deal with Nabal?
Anybody find that scripture right quick?
1st Samuel 25.
>> 1st Samuel 25.
>> I'm there.
>> Pick it up at verse 9.
>> Okay.
>> It says, "And when David's young men
came, they spake to Nabal according to
all those words in the name of David and
ceased.
And Nabal answered David's servants and
said, "Who is David? And who is the son
of Jesse? There be many servants now a
days that break away every man from his
master.
Shall I then take my Shall I then take
my bread and my water and my flesh that
I have killed for my sharers and give it
unto men whom I know not whence they be?
So David's young men turned their way
and went again and came and told him all
those sayings. And David said unto his
men, "Gird ye on every man his sword."
And they girded on every man his sword.
And David also girded on his sword. And
there went up after David about 400 men.
400 men and 200 abode by the stuff.
>> Go ahead. But one of the young men told
Abigail Nabal's wife, saying, "Behold,
David sent messengers out of the
wilderness to salute our master, and he
railed on them." But the men were But
the men were very good unto us, and were
not hurt, neither miss we anything, as
long as we have conversent with them.
When we were in the fields,
then there
In other words, he said, "Look, David
them protected us. They didn't let
nobody,
>> they protected this guy's stock,
>> and David was mad. He put this ward on
him and then all his people." And and
now this servant went and told Nabal's
wife, Abigail, keep reading. And what
happened?
>> There was a wall unto us by both by
night and day. all the while we were
with them kept keeping the sheep. Now
therefore know and consider what thou
wil do for evil is determined against
our master and against all his household
for he is such a son of bile that a man
cannot speak to him.
Then Abigail made haste and took 200
loaves and two bottles of wine and five
sheep ready dressed and five measures of
parched corn and 100 clusters of raisins
and 200 cakes of figs and laid them on
asses.
And she said unto her servants, "Go on
before me. Behold, I come after you."
But she told not her husband Nabal.
>> Go ahead. And
>> and it was so as she rode on the ass
that she came down by the covert of the
hill. And behold, David and his men bea
came down against her, and she met them.
Now David had said, "Surely in vain have
I kept all that his fellow hath in the
wilderness, so that nothing was missed
of all that pertainth to him." and he
requited me evil for good.
So, and more also do God unto the
enemies of David. If I leave of all that
pertain to him by the morning light, any
that pisses against the wall.
And what
>> she going to kill everybody in this
household. Go ahead and read. And when
Abigail saw David, she hasted and
lightened off the ass and fell before
David on her face and bowed herself to
the ground and fell at his feet and
said, "Upon me, my Lord, upon me let
this iniquity be, and let thine
handmade, I pray thee, speak in thine
audience, and hear the words of thine
handmmaid.
Let not my lord I pray thee regard this
man of bilau even Nabal. For as his name
is so is he. Nabal is his name and folly
is with him. But I thine handmade saw
not the young man of my lord whom thou
didest send.
>> Now she later on and told her husband
about it cuz he cuz she saved his whole
household. Can Can you skip to that and
and and finish it?
>> Yeah.
>> Just get down to verse 32.
>> Okay. And David said to Abigail,
"Blessed be the Lord God of Israel,
which sent thee to this day to meet me,
and blessed be thy advice, and blessed
be thou which has kept me this day from
coming to shed blood, and from avenging
myself with mine own."
>> Continue. For in very deed, as the Lord
God of Israel liveth, which hath kept me
back from hurting thee, except thou
hadest haste, and come to meet me,
surely there had not been left unto
Nabal by the morning light any that
pisses against the wall.
>> And you can finish it at verse 38.
>> And it came to pass about 10 days after
the Lord smoked Nabal that he died.
So now she the savior and he end up
dying.
And this woman end up being uh uh David,
one of David's wife. She end up marrying
a king. So you have one that follow her
husband, went along with his father. God
killed both of them. And another wife
that didn't go home with with the father
cuz Nabal mean fool of her husband. He
saved her and all of his servant and God
killed him. So now you got what the book
say.
So the choice is up to you. That's all I
have to say. All right. Hope that
answered your question. And I would like
to say that we have ran out of time. And
we'd like to thank everybody from all
around the world who tuned in with us.
And if you submitted a question and we
didn't get to it, please don't resubmit
it cuz sister Deborah take it. put it in
rotation and we will deal with that
question next week. So until we all come
together again, we say be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as brother
James closes us out.
>> Our Father, which art in heaven,
>> hallowed be thy name, thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread. And forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen. Good night all. Good night
everyone. Good night everyone. Good
night.